Finding Aid for the Jean Renoir Papers PASC.0105
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Part II - Correspondence
  - FEBRUARY 1962
    - Controversy over the rights to LA MARSEILLAISE - letters to and from J.R. and Dido Renoir during post-production work on LE CAPORAL EPINGLE - translations of RENOIR PAR RENOIR - copies of business letters from Ginette Doynel - includes photocopied correspondence. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Loew, David * Doynel, Ginette * CAPORAL EPINGLE, LE * Truffaut, Francois * Weaver, Randolph (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - MARCH 1962
    - Project "Le Faim" - letters to and from J.R. and Dido Renoir during post-production work on LE CAPORAL EPINGLE - news of family and friends - receipts from FRENCH CANCAN. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Griot, Jean * Doynel, Ginette * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * CAPORAL EPINGLE, LE * Werner, Oskar * FAIM, LE (project) (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - APRIL 1962
    - Translations and corrections of RENOIR PAR RENOIR - J.R. at B.F.I. in London - letters to and from J.R. and Dido Renoir - J.R.'s BBC interview with Dilys Powell - reactions to LE CAPORAL EPINGLE. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roud, Richard * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Doynel, Ginette * Rainer, Luise * Scott, Zachary * Weaver, Randolph * Gaut, Pierre * CAPORAL EPINGLE, LE (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - MAY 1962
    - Release of LE CAPORAL EPINGLE - news of friends - translations and corrections of RENOIR PAR RENOIR. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Loew, David * Doynel, Ginette * CAPORAL EPINGLE, LE * RENOIR PAR RENOIR (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - JUNE 1962
    - Release of RENOIR PAR RENOIR - invitations to film festivals - releaes of LE CAPORAL EPINGLE - corrections of RENOIR PAR RENOIR - business correspondence from Ginette Doynel. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Kaufman, Lilian * CAPORAL EPINGLE, LE * Langlois, Henri * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Graetz, Paul * Weaver, Randolph * Renoir, Jacques * Renoir, Claude, Sr. * Braunberger, Pierre * MacGregor, Duncan (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - JULY 1962
    - Dispute over the rights to LE MARSEILLAISE - political turmoil in France - invitations to Venice Film Festival - reactions to LE CAPORAL EPINGLE - translations of RENOIR PAR RENOIR - news of family and friends. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * CAPORAL EPINGLE, LE * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Sen Gupta, Ram * Braunberger, Pierre * Weaver, Randolph * Carbuccia, Adry de * Carbuccia, Jean-Luc de (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - AUGUST 1962
    - Corrections of RENOIR PAR RENOIR - invitations - reactions to LE CAPORAL EPINGLE - news of family and friends. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Roud, Richard * Radha * Carbuccia, Adry de * CAPORAL EPINGLE, LE (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - SEPTEMBER 1962
    - Reactions to LE CAPORAL EPINGLE - political situation in France - "Look" magazine article on RENOIR PAR RENOIR - controversy over copy of LA MARSEILLAISE at the Cinematheque Francaise. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Langlois, Henri * Doynel, Ginette * Bergman, Ingrid * Cavagnac, Guy * Hurlburt, Allen * CAPORAL EPINGLE, LE * RENOIR PAR RENOIR (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - OCTOBER 1962
    - J.R.'s attempt to acquire prints of old films - Cuban missle crisis - political situation in France - invitation to be on Quebec radio - J.R. on BBC - business letters from Ginette Doynel - news of family and friends. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Clarke, Sir Humphrey * Vaughan, Olwen * Truffaut, Francois * Langlois, Henri * Cavagnac, Guy * Braunberger, Pierre * Radha * Kael, Pauline * Renoir, Alain (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - NOVEMBER 1962
    - Release of RENOIR PAR RENOIR - projects - invitations - J.R.'s request for a copy of BBC film interview - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - news of family and friends - English titles for LE CAPORAL EPINGLE - J.R. to speak at U.C.L.A. dinner. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Doynel, Ginette * Braunberger, Pierre * Wolquitt, Eleanor * Weaver, Randolph * Lewin, Albert * CAPORAL EPINGLE, LE (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - DECEMBER 1962
    - Reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - death of Charles Laughton - Christmas greetings - controversy with Cinematheque Francaise over LE MARSEILLAISE rights - J.R. on television to promote RENOIR PAR RENOIR - business letters from Ginette Doynel - news of family and friends. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Laughton, Charles * Simenon, Georges * Truffaut, Francois * Smart, Charles Allen * Doynel, Ginette * Langlois, Henri * Carbuccia, Jean-Luc de * Braunberger, Pierre * Clarke, Sir Humphrey * Smith, Bessie (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - 1963-1969
    - Royalty statements for 1963 through 1969; RENOIR MY FATHER. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - JANUARY 1963
    - Controversy with Cinematheque Francaise over copy of LE MARSEILLAISE - J.R. to receive PhD from U.C.L.A. - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - publicity interviews - J.R. lecture at YMCA - news of family and friends. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Andre, Jacqueline * Renoir, Claude, Jr. * Cezanne, Renee * Braunberger, Pierre * Caron, Leslie * Griot, Jean * Sen Gupta, Ram (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - FEBRUARY 1963
    - Business correspondence from Ginette Doynel - dispute with Cinematheque Francaise over copy of LA MARSEILLAISE - J.R. speech at Wilshire Blvd. Temple - J.R. to receive PhD at U.C.L.A. - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Cezanne, Renee * Carbuccia, Jean-Luc de * Melnitz, William * Seigfried, Earl * L'Herminier, Pierre * Magnin, Rabbi Edgar * MacGregor, Duncan (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - MARCH 1963
    - J.R. invited to U.C.L.A. conference - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - news of family and friends. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bergman, Ingrid * Braunberger, Pierre * Janssen, Werner * Sen Gupta, Ram * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Levin, Irving * Cezanne, Renee * Odets, Clifford (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - APRIL 1963
    - News of family and friends - receipts of German sales of RENOIR PAR RENOIR - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - invitations - J.R. receives honorary PhD from U.C.L.A. - projects - presentation of LE CAPORAL EPINGLE in San Francisco - includes photocopied correspondence. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Godden, Rumer * Frangakis, Nick * Melnitz, William * Valery, Jeanne * Rewald, John * Carbuccia, Jean-Luc de * Carbuccia, Adry de * Braunberger, Pierre * Chandler, Dorothy * Levin, Irving * MacGregor, Duncan * Strauss, Helen * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Smart, Charles Allen * Halpern, Otto (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - MAY 1963
    - Projects - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - J.R. to teach at U.C.L.A. - news of family and friends - J.R. lecture at Arts Club. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Rouart, Julie Manet * Renoir, Claude, Jr. * Cavagnac, Guy * Bergman, Ingrid * Janssen, Werner * Macchi, Guilio * Rouart, Denis * Godden, Rumer * Frangakis, Nick * Kaufman, Lilian (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - JUNE 1963
    - Business correspondence from Ginette Doynel - news of family and friends - invitations - projects "Julienne et Son Amour" and "Le Lever du Rideau" - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Simenon, Georges * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Rewald, John * Renoir, Claude, Sr. * Bazin, Janine * Frangakis, Nick * Chevallier-Munier, Louise * Janssen, Werner * JULIENNE ET SON AMOUR(project) * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - JULY 1963
    - News of family and friends - business correspondence - project "Julienne et Son Amour" - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Bazin, Janine * Gaut, Pierre * Heifetz, Florence * Janssen, Werner * Reiniger, Lotte * Lewin, Millie * Lewin, Albert * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * JULIENNE ET SON AMOUR(project) (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - AUGUST 1963
    - Death of Clifford Odets - project "Le Lever du Rideau" with Leslie Caron - invitations - news of friends. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Caron, Leslie * Doynel, Ginette * Carbuccia, Adry de * Odets, Clifford * Feinstein, Herbert * Kaufman, Lilian * Lewin, Albert * Macchi, Guilio * Smart, Charles Allen * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - SEPTEMBER 1963
    - Projects "Le Lever du Rideau" with Leslie Caron and "Julienne et son Amour" - news of family and friends - letters to and from David Loew re: rights to THE SOUTHERNER - translations of RENOIR PAR RENOIR into different languages -reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - business correspondence - includes photocopied correspondence. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Frangakis, Nick * Caron, Leslie * Bazin, Janine * Loew, David * Doynel, Ginette * Carbuccia, Adry de * Godden, Rumer * Cavagnac, Guy * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Meredith, Burgess * JULIENNE ET SON AMOUR(project) * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - OCTOBER 1963
    - Projects "Julienne et Son Amour" - J.R.'s attempt to get 16mm copy of THE RIVER - Argentine publicity for RENOIR PAR RENOIR - J.R. lectures - invitations - J.R. honored by Hollywood Museum - J.R.'s attempts to get distribution for Kent MacKenzie's film "The Exiles" - news of family and friends. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * MacKenzie, Kent * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Frangakis, Nick * Doynel, Ginette * Langlois, Henri * Metlova, Maria * Carbuccia, Adry de * JULIENNE ET SON AMOUR(project) (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - NOVEMBER 1963
    - Assasination of Pres. John F. Kennedy - news of family and friends - project "Le Lever du Rideau" with Leslie Caron - translations of RENOIR PAR RENOIR - Bosley Crowther request for information on LA GRANDE ILLUSION for his book. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Stausberg, Paula * Blavette, Charles * Loew, David * Caron, Leslie * Doynel, Ginette * Strauss, Helen * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Francen, Leno * Renoir, Alain * GRANDE ILLUSION, LA * Cezanne, Renee * Crowther, Bosley * Radha * Bergman, Ingrid * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - DECEMBER 1963
    - Reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - project "Aspects of Love" - Christmas greetings - lawsuit over infringement of Renoir heir's rights - death of Carl Koch - J.R.'s attempts to get distribution for Kent MacKenzie's film "The Exiles". Includes correspondence regarding or with: * MacKenzie, Kent * Doynel, Ginette * Bradbury, Ray * Tessier, Valentine * Wolquitt, Eleanor * Koch, Carl * Reiniger, Lotte * Stravinsky, Igor * Sen Gupta, Ram * Macchi, Guilio * Renoir, Claude, Jr. * ASPECTS OF LOVE (project) (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - UNDATED 1963
    - Correspondence with several unidentified people. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Pozner, Vladimir (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - JANUARY 1964
    - Death of Carl Koch - news of family and friends - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - project "Le Lever du Rideau" with Leslie Caron. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Rouart, Julie Manet * Caron, Leslie * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Andre, Jacqueline * Ishihara, Shoji * Reiniger, Lotte * Koch, Carl * Leclerc, Georges * Feinstein, Herbert * Milhaud, Darius * Gaut, Pierre * Renoir, Claude, Sr. * Swinburne, Nora * Hughes, Robert * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - FEBRUARY 1964
    - News of friends - J.R.'s attempts to get distribution for Kent MacKenzie's film "The Exiles" - invitations - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - J.R.'s presentation at the Hollywood Museum - projects "Le Lever du Rideau" and "Aspectsof Love". Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Langlois, Henri * Bergman, Ingrid * Doynel, Ginette * MacKenzie, Kent * Strauss, Helen * Huston, John * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Knight, Arthur * Cardiff, Jack * ASPECTS OF LOVE (project) * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - MARCH 1964
    - J.R.'s attempts to get distribution for Kent MacKenzie's film "The Exiles" - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - rights of Pierre-Auguste Renoir's heir to reproductions of his work - information on the Technoscope film process - rights to ORVET - invitations - projects: film about Pierre-Auguste Renoir, "Le Lever du Rideau" and "Julienne et Son Amour". Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Renoir, Claude, Sr. * Doynel, Ginette * Macchi, Guilio * Cavagnac, Guy * Gaut, Pierre * Renoir, Claude, Jr. * Hughes, Robert * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * JULIENNE ET SON AMOUR(project) * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - APRIL 1964
    - Projects "Aspects of Love" and "Le Lever du Rideau" - J.R.'s attempts to get distribution for Kent MacKenzie's film, "The Exiles" - J.R.'s operation - plans for J.R. birthday tribute on German television - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - news of family and friends. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Frangakis, Nick * Langlois, Henri * Braunberger, Pierre * MacKenzie, Kent * Jutra, Claude * Kaufman, Lilian * Renoir, Claude, Jr. * Wolquitt, Eleanor * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Robson, Mark * Kresel, Lee * Strauss, Helen * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) * ASPECTS OF LOVE (project) (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - MAY 1964
    - J.R.'s operation - project "Le Lever du Rideau" - J.R.'s attempts to get distribution for Kent MacKenzie's film "The Exiles" - news of family and friends. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Renoir, Alain * Curtis, Tony * Doynel, Ginette * Braunberger, Pierre * MacKenzie, Kent * Sen Gupta, Ram * Renoir, Claude, Jr. * Renoir, Claude, Sr. * Peck, Sedley * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - JUNE 1964
    - News of family and friends - J.R. recovers from operation - project "Le Lever du Rideau". Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Frangakis, Nick * Doynel, Ginette * Braunberger, Pierre * Leclerc, Georges * Lourie, Eugene * Curtis, Tony * Renoir, Claude, Sr. * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Strauss, Helen * Valery, Jeanne * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - JULY 1964
    - Projects "La Celestine" and "Le Lever du Rideau" - J.R. film retrospective in Germany - invitations - news of family and friends - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Braunberger, Pierre * Doynel, Ginette * Krim, Villem * Odets, Walter * Renoir, Alain * CELESTINE, LA (project) * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - AUGUST 1964
    - Project "Le Lever du Rideau" - news of family and friends - invitations - RENOIR PAR RENOIR translation in German. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Renoir, Claude, Sr. * Renoir, Alain * Bergman, Ingrid * Braunberger, Pierre * Doynel, Ginette * Magnin, Rabbi Edgar * Macchi, Guilio * Strasberg, Paula * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Curtis, Tony * LEVER DU RIDEAU, LE (project) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - SEPTEMBER 1964
    - Project "Le Celestine" - J.R.'s attempts to find distribution for Kent MacKenzie's film "The Exiles" - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - translations for the book - J.R. tribute on German T.V. - project: film based on RENOIR PAR RE NOIR. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Braunberger, Pierre * Andre, Jacqueline * MacKenzie, Kent * Hughes, Robert * Doynel, Ginette * Curtis, Tony * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Renoir, Claude, Jr. * CELESTINE, LA (project) (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - OCTOBER 1964
    - News of family and friends - translations of RENOIR PAR RENOIR - invitations - J.R. tribute on German T.V. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Odets, Walter * Varda, Agnes * Blavette, Charles * Braunberger, Pierre * Pozner, Vladimir * Kaufman, Lilian * Knittel, Robert * Strasberg, Paula * Doynel, Ginette * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Weaver, Randolph (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - NOVEMBER 1964
    - Donation of Clifford Odets's death mask to Harvard University - news of family - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - Pierre-Auguste Renoir's heir's legal dispute. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Rotha, Paul * Levin, Harry * Doynel, Ginette * RENOIR PAR RENOIR (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - DECEMBER 1964
    - Christmas greetings - sale of J.R.'s old silent films - news of family and friends - invitations. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Signoret, Simone * Montand, Yves * Sen Gupta, Ram * Knight, Arthur * Braunberger, Pierre * Pons, Lily * Weaver, Randolph * Walters, Patricia * Blavette, Charles * Curtis, Tony * Griot, Jean * Odets, Walter * O'Neill, Charles * Renoir, Claude, Jr. * Doynel, Ginette (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - JANUARY 1965
    - J.R. writing LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - business correspondence - rights for exhibition of J.R.'s silent films - news of friends - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - J.R. festival on Canadian T.V. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Loew, David * Braunberger, Pierre * Simenon, Georges * Weaver, Randolph * Walters, Patricia * Renoir, Claude, Sr. * Renoir, Claude, Jr. * Radha * Caron, Leslie * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Cavagnac, Guy * Jutra, Claude * Reiniger, Lotte * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - FEBRUARY 1965
    - Deposit of silent film negatives at the Cinematheque Francaise - completion of LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - news of family and friends - J.R.'s desire to distribute the film "Goldstein" through "La Cie Jean Renoir" - business correspondence. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Braunberger, Pierre * Wolquitt, Eleanor * Doynel, Ginette * Rouart, Julie Manet * Renoir, Claude, Jr. * Odets, Walter * Cavagnac, Guy * Godden, Rumer (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - MARCH 1965
    - Translation of LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - invitations - news of friends. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Strauss, Helen * Ryan, Thomas * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Knight, Arthur * Knittel, Robert (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - APRIL 1965
    - News of friends - J.R. on BBC radio - translation of LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - legal questions concerning plaster casts made of statues (allegedly) made by Guino under the direction of Pierre-Auguste Renoir. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Weaver, Randolph * Tessier, Valentine * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Braunberger, Pierre * Godden, Rumer * Reiniger, Lotte * Segal, Erich * Braque, Marcelle * Kerr, Clark * Knittel, Robert * Simenon, Georges * Doynel, Ginette * Bradford, Ned (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - MAY 1965
    - J.R. on BBC radio - translations of LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - news of friends - re-release of LA REGLE DU JEU - business correspondence. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Olaf, Pierre * Peck, Sedley * Bradford, Ned * Bergman, Ingrid * Bazin, Janine * Caron, Leslie * Cassan, Marguerite * Knittel, Robert * Lewin, Albert * Doynel, Ginette (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - JUNE 1965
    - News of family and friends - work on translations of LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - invitations - re-release of LA REGLE DU JEU - business correspondence. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Weaver, Randolph * Ross, Lillian * O'Neill, Charles * Odets, Walter * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Bazin, Janine * Curtis, Tony * Ishihara, Shoji * Knittel, Robert * Lourie, Eugene * REGLE DU JEU, LA * Chamberlin, Philip * Bradford, Ned * Doynel, Ginette (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - JULY 1965
    - News of friends - J.R.'s lecture at U.C. Santa Barbara - translations of LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - project "The Heart Is A Lonely Hunter" - publication of LA REGLE DU JEU - business correspondence. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Sesonske, Alexander * Tournaire, Helene * O'Neill, Charles * Bradford, Ned * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Chamberlin, Philip * Lourie, Eugene * Ryan, Thomas * Chaudeau, Robert * Feinstein, Herbert * Doynel, Ginette * HEART IS A LONELY HUNTER, THE (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - AUGUST 1965
    - News of family and friends - invitations - projects "The Heart Is A Lonely Hunter","Le Faim" with Oskar Werner, and a re-make of LES BAS FONDS with Warren Beatty - J.R. film festival at Colorado State University - Watts riots in Los Angeles. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Weaver, Randolph * Renoir, Claude, Jr. * Odets, Walter * Odets, Nora * Radha * Curtis, Tony * Lewin, Albert * Doynel, Ginette * FAIM, LE (project) * HEART IS A LONELY HUNTER, THE (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - SEPTEMBER 1965
    - News of family and friends - invitations - projects - corrections of translation of LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - lawsuit over statues (allegedly) created under the direction of Pierre-Auguste Renoir. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Werner, Oskar * Slade, Jean * Amberg, George * Bergman, Ingrid * Radha * Enters, Angna * Feinstein, Herbert * Greenspan, Lou * Godden, Rumer * Knittel, Robert * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - OCTOBER 1965
    - Project "Aspects of Love" - translations for and rights to LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - news of family and friends - business correspondence. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Wolquitt, Eleanor * Werner, Oskar * Strauss, Helen * Rainer, Luise * Renoir, Claude, Sr. * Odets, Walter * Odets, Nora * Boynton, Judd * Braunberger, Pierre * Bradford, Ned * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Cavagnac, Guy * Curtis, Tony * Enters, Angna * Knittel, Robert * Doynel, Ginette * ASPECTS OF LOVE (project) (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - NOVEMBER 1965
    - Plans for the publication of LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - project "Aspects of Love" - news of friends - beginning plans for LE PETIT THEATRE DE JEAN RENOIR (working title: C'est la Revolution"). Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Gallimard, Claude * Gaut, Pierre * Caron, Leslie * Weaver, Randolph * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Odets, Nora * Andre, Jacqueline * Braunberger, Pierre * Bradford, Ned * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Bazin, Janine * Knittel, Robert * ASPECTS OF LOVE (project) (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - DECEMBER 1965
    - Invitations - publication of LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - news of family and friends - project "Aspects of Love" - reactions to RENOIR PAR RENOIR - beginnings of LE PETIT THEATRE DE JEAN RENOIR (working title:"C'est la Revolution") - business correspondence. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bradford, Ned * Wolquitt, Eleanor * Gallimard, Claude * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Werner, Oskar * Weaver, Randolph * Sen Gupta, Ram * Rouart, Julie Manet * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Miller, Henry * Lewin, Albert * Braunberger, Pierre * Bergman, Ingrid * Breen, Thomas * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Doynel, Ginette * ASPECTS OF LOVE (project) (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - JANUARY 1966
    - Christmas greetings - J.R. in hospital - corrections of LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - death of Dido Renoir's mother and condolences - invitations - project "Aspects of Love" and "La Revolution" (prototype of LE PETIT THEATRE DE JEAN RENOIR). Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Gaut, Pierre * Godden, Rumer * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Knittel, Robert * Kaufman, Lilian * Bradford, Ned * Boyer, Charles * Braunberger, Pierre * Curtis, Tony * Clair, Rene * Werner, Oskar * ASPECTS OF LOVE (project) (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - FEBRUARY 1966
    - News of family and friends - corrections and translations of LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES - invitations - projects - cinema named for J.R. in France - death of Dido Renoir's mother. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Griot, Jean * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Pagnol, Marcel * Knittel, Robert * Lewin, Albert * Dunne, Irene * Braunberger, Pierre * Bazin, Janine * Werner, Oskar (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - MARCH 1966